Today you all have gathered here
今天你们都聚集一堂
to do the Guru Puja.
做导师普祭
Your Guru is a Mother first and then a Guru
你们的导师首先是一个母亲 然后是一个导师
and that has given Me a greater help.
而这已经给我帮了很大的忙
We have had before also many Guru Pujas,
我们之前也有过很多次的导师普祭
mostly in England.
几乎都在英国
And you should wonder why
而你们会感到奇怪 为什么
Mother always somehow is doing Guru Puja in London.
母亲总是在伦敦举办导师普祭
The time falls in such a way that it is in Guru Puja,
时间就刚好那样落在导师普祭中
I am here, during that time I have to be in London.
我在这里 在那个时间段我不得不在伦敦
So many years we have been doing Guru Puja in England.
那么多年我们都在伦敦做导师普祭
All things happen if according to ritambhara pragya
所有事情的发生 如果按照ritambhara pragya
then there must be some reason
然后那一定有一些原因
why Mother is here in England for a Guru Puja.
为什么母亲在这里 在英国为了一个导师普祭
It is stated in the Puranas that
这在往世书中记载了
the Adi Guru Datattreya
太初导师
worshipped Mother
崇拜母亲
along the banks of the river Tamasa.
沿着Tamasa河的岸边
Tamasa is the same as your Thames
Tamasa河和你们的泰晤士河一样
and He himself came and worshipped here.
而他自己来这里做崇拜
And the druids, those who had
德鲁伊教团员  那些已经
the manifestation of the Stonehenge and all that,
显示巨石阵的人和所有那些
are originated from that time in this great country of Shiva,
都起源于那段时间 在这伟大的湿婆神之国度
of the Spirit.
这灵魂
So the Spirit resides here as in the heart of human beings,
因此 灵魂就居住在这里就像在人类的心中一样
and the Sahasrara
而顶轮
is in the Himalayas where Sadashiva exists at the Kailasha.
是在喜马拉雅 至高湿婆神所在的冈仁波齐山
This is the great secret
这就是最大的秘密
of we having so many Guru Pujas here.
我们要在这里举办这么多场导师普祭
To culminate it today and to this special type of Guru Puja
为了今天达到它的高潮 为了这个特殊类型的导师普祭
in the year of the sixtieth birthday of your Mother
在你们母亲的第六十个生日的这一年
is, has a special, very, very special significance
是 有一个特殊的 非常非常特殊的意义
because is the Guru Sashti -
因为是 导师 Sashti
is the sixty years of your Guru has been celebrated today.
今天是你们的导师已经被庆祝的六十年了
And that's how it's a very big occasion that you all have gathered
这就是你们如何在这样一个非常重大的时刻都汇聚一堂
under the influence of again ritambhara pragya.
再次在ritambhara pragya的影响下
So all that has happened has happened by the nature's own gift to you
因此是在大自然自己的运作下给你的礼物 所有这些都已经发生 已经发生了
and everything has worked out so well
而所有的一切都成就得非常好
because that was the desire of the Divine
因为那就是上天的愿望
and the design of the Divine.
和上天的设计
So the river Thames, which we call Her as Thames -
因此 这Thames河 那条我们叫它泰晤士的河
you see, English have a method of making everything English.
你看 英语就是有一种方法可以把一切都英语化
Like Bombay they made it - Mumbai was Bombay,
就像孟买 他们把 Mumbai弄成Bombay
you see, like Calcutta, like all other words just like that.
你看 就像加尔各答 像所有其他的单词就像那样
Like Varanasi was made into Benares,
就像瓦拉纳西被弄成 Benares
River Thames which was really Tamsa was called as Thames.
泰晤士河 真正的Tamsa 被叫成Thames
Now from the name Tamsa one should know
现在从泰晤士河的名字你可以知道
that is a place of Tamo Guna.
那就是Tamo Guna的地方
Is a place where left-sided resided since long.
就是那左边的在很久以前就存在的地方
So people were very worshipful, left-sided people, emotional type,
因此人们是非常虔诚的 偏左的人们 感性的类型
and they worshipped God more
而且他们崇拜上帝多于
than that they went into yagyas and all that.
他们去看 yagyas 表演或者其他什么的
And Datattreya lived here
而 Datattreya 住在这里
and meditated on the banks of River Thames.
在泰晤士河的岸边冥想
That's why Guru puja here has to give us a great background
这就是为什么在这里做导师普祭 给我们的伟大的背景
for your awakening of the Guru Principle.
为了唤醒你们的导师原理
We have to go to the roots of everything
我们要到达每一件事情的根本
so that we understand the importance of it.
这样我们才能理解它的重要性
Unless and until you know the roots and the traditions behind
除非而且直到你们知道根本和传统背后的东西
you cannot understand the depth,
你们是不能够理解它的深度的
the gravity, the intensity of any puja.
任何一个普祭的重心 强度
Today we have gathered here to do the Guru Puja, again.
今天我们再一次汇聚一堂做导师普祭
The reason is we have got a Guru Principle within ourselves
这个原因就是我们已经在我们的内在获取了导师原理
as I told you last time
就像我上次告诉你们的
and also I have given elaborately
也是我用心良苦给你们的
the Ten Commandments as expressed within us
十诫已经在我们内在明示
which are describing the different
就是描述了不同的那个
the different types of essences within us.
在我们内在的精髓的不同类型
The essence of Guru Puja has to be awakened within us.
导师普祭的精髓已经在我们内在被唤醒
That's how we are having this program here.
这就是我们为何能够在这里举办活动
Now it is important
现在 这非常重要
that we have to establish
那就是我们一定要建立
the dharma within us.
正法在我们内在
Without the dharma you cannot have the ascent.
没有正法你无法升进
And as I have told you before that the cleanliness
而就像我之前已经告诉过你们 这个清洁
of your being
对你的生命体
depends on how much dharma you follow, religiously.
依赖于你虔诚地遵从了多少正法
At the time of Moses
在摩西时代
it was worked out
它被成就了
and all the rules and regulations
所有的规则和规矩
were created for realized souls.
都是为觉醒的灵魂而创造的
But as I read in one of the books - it was very good,
但是当我在一本书中读到的时候 它非常棒
because if I had said this, people would not have believed -
因为如果我已经说过这个 人们会不相信
that it had to be changed.
它已经被改变了
I think during the speech the children should not be here,
我想讲话期间 孩子不应该在这里
it's better to take them out.
最好把他们带出去
After the speech you can bring them along - those who make noises.
讲话后你可以带上他们 那些要制造噪声的
Those who are quiet it's all right,
那些安静的没关系
but those who are making noises you better bring them out.
但是那些制造噪声的孩子你最好把他们带出去
If they are going to make noises, better to be out or near the door
如果他们继续制造噪声 最好出去或者在门边
so that if they make noises you can get out,
这样他们一制造噪声你就可以让他们出去
so there is no disturbance.
这样就没有干扰了
And during the puja is all right, you could be at the gate,
在普祭期间是可以的 你可以在门边
door or some place from where you can go.
门口或者一些你可以出去的地方
So the laws and regulations that were given to human beings
因此给予人类的这些律法和规矩
were actually for the realized souls who would understand.
实际上是为那些能够理解的觉醒的灵
But when Moses must have discovered the way human beings are,
但是当摩西发现当时人类的状况
He must have changed them to very strict rules,
他就必须变成非常严苛的规则
because with human beings as they are,
因为对像他们这样的人类
one has to be extremely strict.
你必须极度严苛
They can't understand anything but fear.
除了恐惧它们什么都不能理解
If you have
如果你有
a stick in your hand, you can put them right.
一根棒子在你手中 你就能让他们乖乖的
Without that stick human beings won't listen.
没有那根棒子 人类就不听话
They are only all right if there's a fear.
他们只有在恐惧中才能乖乖的
Now if you see
现在如果你看
the today condition of all the nations,
如今所有民族的情况
those who are having leaders, or prime ministers, or presidents
那些有领袖的 或者首相 或者总统的
they are all people extremely strict,
他们都是极度严苛的人
very dominating and very dry.
非常专横的而且也非常干枯
And normally people like such people.
而通常人们喜欢那样的人
Even Hitler succeeded because of that nature.
甚至是希特勒的成功也是因为本性
So the character of a guru so far
因此到目前为止导师的品性
has been of a very strict nature
要具备非常严苛的本性
for people who are not realized.
是为了那些还没有自觉的人
Normally a guru doesn't - a good guru, Satguru,
通常地一个导师不是  一个好导师 Satguru
He doesn't like to talk to people much.
他就不喜欢跟人说太多话
They throw stones
他们丢石头
or they don't like to talk to people
或者他们不喜欢和
who are not realized.
那些没有自觉的人说话
But if they are realized then these Gurus change their attitude
但是如果他们是觉醒的 然后这些导师就会改变他们的态度
towards the people who want to see them.
对待那些想见他们的人
There is a tremendous difference
有天壤之别
between a person who is a realized and non-realized
在觉醒和没有觉醒的人之间
in the protocol of God.
在上帝的礼仪中
A man may be the king or anything, he'll be asked to sit outside.
一个人他可以是国王或任何人 他都要被要求站到外面
It has nothing to do with what position you enjoy.
这和你享受着怎样的职位没有任何关系
As long as he is a realized soul and not possessed
只要他是一个觉醒的灵 而且不是着魔的
he is given the highest position.
他就被赐予最高的职位
But if you are possessed then also the Guru will tell him
但是如果你被附体 那么导师就要告诉你
that "You get out from here,
你给我从这出去
first get rid of your possession and then come."
首先你要弃绝你的财产然后来过
And all these strict rules were there,
所有这些严苛的规定都在那儿
that such and such person must be killed,
这样和这样的人要被杀掉
such and such person must be given a punishment
这样和这样的人要给予惩罚
of cutting the hands, cutting the feet,
剁了手 剁了脚
even absolutely destroying the eyes.
更有甚者完全挖掉眼睛
This was done because they were not realized souls.
做这些因为他们不是觉醒的灵魂
It was the great realization of Moses, I think,
摩西有非常伟大的意识 我想
that He took to another kind of law which is known as Sharia now
他带来了另一种类型的律法 现在以伊斯兰教教法著称
and that's what the Muslims are following.
那就是穆斯林遵循的
In a way it's good I think,
从某种角度来看 我想它是很好的
because people who are now normal people really deserve such a rule,
因为现在那些普通的人真正应得这样的规矩
but it should not be so fanatical that you cannot discriminate
但是他不应该那样狂热以至于你不能辨别
between a realized soul and a non-realized soul.
在觉醒的灵和非觉醒的灵之间
Now the Guru within you
现在你内在的导师
will be awakened if you are strict with yourself.
将会被唤醒如果你对自己严格地话
That's one point is very important.
这一点非常重要
Unless and until you are strict with yourself
除非而且直到你对自己严格
the Guru will not be awakened within you.
导师是不会在你内在被唤醒的
People who are lazy lumps, who cannot sacrifice anything,
那些懒骨头的人 他们不能为任何事情有所牺牲
who are very fond of comfort can never be gurus, take it from Me.
那些非常喜欢舒适的人是永远无法成为导师的 我可以下这个断语
They can be good administrators, they can be anything,
他们可以是很好的管理员 他们可以是任何职业
but never a guru.
但是绝不可能是一个导师
A guru should be willing to live the way he has to live.
一个导师应该乐意以他必须的方式生活
He should be able to sleep on stones,
他应该可以睡在石头上
he should be able to sleep under any circumstances.
他应该在任何环境中都可以睡觉
Not that the disciple should force on him,
不是门徒要强加于他
but it should be his own nature, that he can adjust himself.
但是是他自己的本性 那就是他可以调整他自己
Comfort cannot crawl on a guru.
舒适不能控制一个导师
Now those who want your Guru Principle to be awakened
现在那些想要你们的导师原理被唤醒的人
must know that you should not ask for comfort.
要知道你们不应该要求舒适
Even for a thing like that, yesterday you saw the dancing,
即便是一件像那样的事 昨天我看见你们在跳舞
one has to do real tapasya.
你要做真正的苦行
Intensive tapasya you have to do,
集中的苦行你们要修
you cannot learn even a thing like dancing
你没法学会哪怕是一件事 像跳舞
without going into a penance about it.
如果没有做关于它的苦行
So a guru has to go through all penances is important.
所以一个导师要通过所有的苦行 非常重要
Sahaja Yogi need not go, but a guru Sahaja Yogi has to do it.
霎哈嘉瑜伽仕不需要做 但是一个导师型的霎哈嘉瑜伽仕就需要做苦行
We have to have penances,
我们一定要有苦行
and the penance can be any kind of desire you have.
而这苦行可以是任何一种你渴望的
Say, supposing you are very fond of food,
假定 假设你非常喜欢事物
just don't eat the food that you want to eat.
那就不吃你喜欢吃的事物
If you are very fond of sweet food,
如果你非常喜欢甜食
then eat something very bitter, raised to power hundred and eight.
那就吃一些非常苦的108次方
And if you are fond of some sort of a very ...
如果你喜欢一些类型的
- as Indians are, sometimes -
就像印度人 有些时候
... very spicy food then eat so bland the food, without salt.
非常辣的事物 那就吃一些白味的食物 没有盐的那种
Teach your tongue to behave itself.
教你的舌头去自己守规矩
It doesn't behoove a guru to put his attention to food.
一个导师没有必要把他的注意力放在食物上
I have seen some of the Sahaja Yogis, they are all right
我见过一些霎哈嘉瑜伽练习者 他们挺好的
when the food is there, quite concentrated,
当食物在那的时候 非常专注
but when it comes to the programme they have no concentration.
但是当到活动中他们就不专心了
Is a sad thing, such people cannot be gurus. They can be cooks, good,
这是非常难过的 这样的人没法做导师 他们可以做厨师 很好
or could be food-tasters or something like that.
或者可以做美食家 或者就像那样的一些
Will suit them better, but if they have to be gurus
会很适合他们 但是如果他们要做导师
they must learn to control their tongue and their desires.
他们就必须学会控制他们的舌头和他们的欲望
I mean, fasting is a good thing for Sahaja Yogis, fasting is very good.
我的意思是 禁食对于霎哈嘉瑜伽练习者来说是非常好的事 禁食非常好
All the time they are worried, what are we going to have for lunch,
他们总是在担忧 我们中午要吃什么
what are we going to have for dinner?
我们晚餐要吃什么
Such people cannot have their Guru Principle awakened,
这样的人他们的导师原理不能被唤醒
neither they can be gurus. So please be careful.
他们也没法成为导师 所以请注意
The guru must have control over the tongue.
导师一定要控制他们的舌头
He must know when to get angry
他必须知道什么时候要生气
and when to be gentle.
什么时候要温和
He must know what to say when,
他必须知道什么时候要说些什么
how much to say.
要说多少
That's why many gurus have been more effective by not speaking.
这就是为什么很多导师通过沉默为了更加有效果
Silence is the best way you can help others,
沉默是帮助他人的最好方式
but when it comes to explaining Sahaja Yoga, you should speak.
但是当要解释霎哈嘉瑜伽的时候 你就要说
But I have seen with some people they are very eloquent
但是我见过一些人 他们非常雄辩
when it comes to nonsensical things,
当说起无聊的事情的时候
but when it comes to Sahaja Yoga, they don't know anything
但是当要说霎哈嘉瑜伽 他们啥都不知道
about Sahaja Yoga.
关于霎哈嘉瑜伽
So you have to be the master of Sahaja Yoga,
因此你要成为霎哈嘉瑜伽的精通者
if you have to be a Guru,
如果你要成为一个导师
not only in talking, but in your behaviour, in everything.
不只是在言谈上 还要在你的行为上 在所有的事情中
And the karamat
而这karamat
is the ...
就是
I don't know if you use charismatic-word, charismatic they call it
我不知道你是否会用神赐的词 他们称它神赐于能力的
or you say, the one how to do it
或者你可以说 那个怎样做
how to raise the Kundalini, how to put it at the Sahasrara,
这样提升昆达里尼 怎样把它安放在顶轮
how to break the Sahasrara, all these things you must know,
怎样突破顶轮 所有这些事情你必须知道
how to spend your knowledge is viniyoga in Sanskrit.
怎样传播你的知识 在梵语里是 viniyoga
Guru principle is awakened in a person
导师原理在一个人内在被唤醒
when he himself has achieved something.
当他自己已经达成了一些事
Imagine a half-baked guru going along talking as a Guru.
想象一下一个半生不熟的导师像一个导师一样一直说话
He'll end up as a disciple ultimately.
他将最终以一个门徒的身份而终结
So you have to be master of your own,
因此你必须要成为你自己的主人
but when the Guru Principle comes in
但是当导师原理达成
you have to give it to others,
你要把它给予他人
it's a question of giving it to others.
给予他人这是一个问题
So you have to be at a higher level to give it to others,
因此你要达到一个更高的水平 去给予他人
have to be at a very high level.
要达到一个非常高的水平
If you are attached to money, if you are attached to food,
如果你执着于金钱 如果你执着于食物
if you are attached to mundane things of life, you cannot give.
如果你执着于生活中世俗的事情 你就不能给予
Now the higher state than that can be achieved,
现在更高的境界可以达成
which is naturally in Me, but can be achieved,
那自然地在我内在 但是是可以达成
is that you don't have to have any dependence like that,
那就是你不用像那样有任何依赖
that any rules and regulations,
那任何的规则和规矩
like saying that I will have no worry about food,
就像说我将对食物没有任何担忧
I should fast, this, that -
我要禁食 这样 那样
it all ends up. When you eat but don't eat,
所有的都完结 当你吃或不吃
that's the state one should have,
那就是你要达到的境界
that you are eating the food
那就是你在吃食物
and if you ask, "Did you have your lunch?"
如果你问 你吃了午餐吗
"I don't know ..."
我不知道
"Will you have your lunch?"
你要吃午餐吗
"I don't know ..."
我不知道
Absolutely indifferent to the problems of the body.
完全对身体的问题漠不关心
"Where did you sleep?"
你在哪里睡觉
"I don't know ..."
我不知道
"What did you eat, what will you have?"
你吃了什么 你会有什么
"I don't know ..."
我不知道
This kind of a state is called ateeta state where you go beyond
这种类型的境界叫做ateeta 境界你要超越到那里
and whatever you do, you are doing it
无论你做什么 你就是在做
because it is to be done. Without paying any attention to it,
因为它就是要完成 不放任何注意力
is automatic.
就是自动的
Nothing is important, but this is -
没有什么是重要的 但是这个是
before becoming ateeta you have to tell yourself,
在成为 ateeta之前 你要告诉你自己
"Nothing is important," you see, is a, avir bhava
什么都不重要 你看 就是 avir bhava
they call it, is a kind of a drama you have to put in.
他们称它 是一种戏剧你要把它放进去
"Oh, nothing is important, this carpet is not important,
噢 没有什么是重要的 这些地毯不重要
I should try to sleep on the cement."
我应该尝试在水泥地上睡觉
First you have to do that.
首先你要那样做
But after some time it happens
但是一段时间以后 就会发生这样的事
that you don't remember whether you slept on the cement
你就不记得是否睡在水泥地上了
or on a cot, "Where did I sleep? I don't know."
或者在一个简易床上 我睡在哪里的 我不知道
That is the ateeta state.
那就是ateeta境界
And that state is to be achieved now by many Sahaja Yogis-
那种境界 现在需要很多霎哈嘉瑜伽仕去达成
in a state where you go beyond.
在一种超越的状态中
Say there is somebody who is before you and you have to get angry.
假设有一些人在你面前 你生气了
All right, you give them left, right, left, right nicely
好的 你给他们左一巴掌 右一巴掌 左一巴掌 右一巴掌 非常好
and then you are smiling next moment.
然后下一刻你就笑了
Did you get angry with that person? "I don't know, did I?"
你对那个人发火了吗 我不知道 我发火了吗
Like Buddha once said something
就像佛陀有一次说了什么
in one village
在一个小村庄
and there was a horrible fellow who got up
那有一个可怕的家伙 他站起来了
and said lots of things to him.
然后对佛陀说了很多
And when He went to the next village the fellow felt
然后当他去下一个村庄的时候 那个家伙感觉
that "Oh, I should not have done that," Left Vishuddi, perhaps.
噢 我不应该那样做 左喉轮 有可能
So he went down and said, "I am sorry Sir, I have said so
因此他就蹲下说 先生 我错了 我说了那些
and I should not have said it,
而我就不应该说
I didn't know You are the enlightened one,
我不知道你就是那个觉醒的人
so it happened, so forgive me."
所以我那样做了 请原谅我吧
He said "When, where did you say?"
他说 什么时候 你在什么地方说的
He said, "In the last village."
他说 在上一个村庄
"Oh, everything in the last village I have left there alone
哦 所有的都是在上一个村庄啊 我已经把它们单独留在那里了
and I don't trouble with it."
我也没觉得烦恼
That is the ateeta state that you have to reach.
那就是你要达到的ateeta的境界
So even not to feel, it's not important.
因此 甚至是不用感觉 它一点都不重要
These identifications when they drop out completely
这样的认同当他们完全脱离
then you are doing things in akarma state,
然后你做事情就在akarma 境界中
where, like sun is shining it doesn't know it is shining.
那里 像太阳发光 它并不知道它在发光
When the vibrations are flowing you don't know it is flowing.
当能量在流动 你不知道它在流动
Already it has started working in you.
它已经开始在你身上运作了
You are surprised, you raise the hands and the Kundalini is rising.
你很吃惊 你抬起你的手 昆达里尼就升起来了
You don't know you are raising the Kundalini actually.
你实际上不知道你提升了昆达里尼
How do you raise it?
你怎样提升它的
You don't know, that's it.
你不知道 那就是了
That state has already started ateeta in you,
那样的境界ateeta已经在你内在运作了
but get it established in every walk of life,
但是要建立它在生活中的每一步
everything, that you go beyond.
每一件事 你要超越
And if you can manage that,
而如果你可以处理它
that's the highest that you have to reach.
那就是你要达成的最高境界
Now with the incarnations it's very different,
对于化身来说 是非常不同的
it's the other way round.
是相反的
Everything is the other way round.
所有的一切都是相反的
They don't have to do any tapasya.
他们不需要做任何的苦行
They don't have to starve, they don't have to cleanse themselves,
他们不需要挨饿 他们不需要清理他们自己
whatever they do is the punya.
他们做什么事都是punya福德
They don't have to collect punyas either.
他们根本都不需要积累福德
If they kill somebody it is dharma.
如果他们杀了某个人 它就是正法
If they hit somebody it is the dharma.
如果他们打了某个人 它就是正法
Nothing they do wrong.
他们没有做错任何事
They are absolutely immaculate.
他们是完全完美的
If they deceive someone, they cheat someone,
如果他们蒙蔽某人 他们欺骗某人
it's perfectly all right.
他是完全完美的
Because for a higher goal you have to give up the smaller goals.
因为为了更高的目标你要放弃那些小目标
It's justified in our day-to-day life you'll see,
你会看到在我们的日常生活中 这被调整
that when you are defending your country,
当你防护你的国家
there is an enemy on you, if you have to defend your country
那有一个你们的敌人 如果你要防护你的国家
you cannot slay him.
你不能杀害他
You can cheat him, diplomatically you can befool him.
你可以欺骗他 你可以圆滑地愚弄他
Is allowed, why?
这是允许的 为什么
Because for a higher goal you have to give up the smaller goal.
因为为了一个更高的目标你要放弃小的目标
But for an incarnation it is always the higher goal.
但是对于一个化身来说 这总是有更高的目标
He is not bothered about smaller goals at all.
他一点也不会被小目标而烦扰
He doesn't have to weigh, think, rationalize
他不必去掂量 思考 找理由
or to train himself or do some drama or anything, it's all done.
或者去训练他自己 或者演一些戏剧或者任何事情 那已经完成了
Even the movement, every movement, every movement of an incarnation
甚至是行动 化身的每一个行动 每一个行动
has a ripple in it, which is for the good.
都有它内在的涟漪 都是为了好事
There is nothing, not even a moment is such
一点都没有 甚至是一个瞬间都不是
which is not for the good of the world.
对世界不好的
So the incarnation is a very different thing,
因此化身是非常不一样
that is not to be achieved, that has to be.
那是不可能被达成的 而是已经就那样
Now for example
现在举个例子
the incarnation is the bhokta, is the enjoyer,
化身就是 这bhokta 就是享受者
He is the enjoyer of everything.
他就是万事万物的享受者
Many people, say, have created,
很多人 假设 已经创造
now we have a carpet here from Turkey.
现在我们这里有一个从土耳其来的地毯
These carpets were created by Turkish peoples
这些地毯是土耳其人制作的
some time back for an incarnation to sit.
一些时候是让化身坐的
So the ritambhara pragya will bring it round in such a way
因此这个 ritambhara pragya 会以这样的方式把它带来
that at least I see it,
至少我看到它
or I have it,
或者我拥有它
so that their souls will be blessed,
以便他们的灵魂会被祝福
so that they feel nice.
所以他们感觉很好
Like Michelangelo has made that not for popes, I can tell you.
就像米开朗基罗不是为教皇而造 我可以告诉你们
and not for all the rubbish people who go there.
也不是为到那里去的那些毫无价值的人
Neither Blake did all that work
布莱克创作的所有作品
for the useless people who want to go and see nude artists.
也不是为那些想去看裸体艺术的无用的人
It was all done for the incarnation to see.
它全部都是为了化身看而创造的
That's the way they have blessed the most,
那就是他们最大程度地获得祝福的方式
because they are beyond, nothing touches them, nothing is important,
因为他们已经超越 什么都不能触碰他们 什么都不重要